Cops without limits. Thieves without fear.
Den of Thieves is a crime, thriller, action film directed by Christian Gudegast.
A gritty crime saga which follows the lives of an elite
unit of the LA County Sheriff's Dept.
and the state's most successful bank robbery crew as the outlaws plan a
seemingly impossible heist on the Federal Reserve Bank.
'Big Nick' O'Brien, played by Gerard Butler.
Ray Merrimen, played by Pablo Schreiber.
Donnie Wilson, played by O'Shea Jackson Jr..
Enson Levoux, played by 50 Cent.
Holly, played by Meadow Williams.
Benny 'Borracho' Magalon, played by Maurice Compte.
Den of Thieves (released in some countries as Criminal Squad) is a 2018 American
action crime film written, produced and directed by Christian Gudegast.
It stars Gerard Butler, Pablo Schreiber, Curtis Jackson, O'Shea Jackson
Jr., Evan Jones, Dawn Olivieri, Mo McRae, and Max Holloway.
In the film, a Los Angeles County Sheriff’s Department deputy gang look to stop a crew of thieves
consisting of ex-MARSOC Marines that are planning to rob the Federal Reserve in Los Angeles.
Den of Thieves was distributed by STXfilms and released
in the United States on January 19, 2018.
The film received mixed reviews and grossed $80 million worldwide.
A sequel, Den of Thieves 2: Pantera, was released on
January 10, 2025 by Lionsgate Films.
The film explores themes of police brutality,
detective, fbi, assault rifle, deputy sheriff.
The tone is dark and intense.